The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: All right, today we continue our exciting adventure
教授：好的，今天我们继续激动人心的冒险
into dynamic programming.
进入动态编程。
Are you excited?
你兴奋吗？
I'm excited, super excited.
我很兴奋，非常兴奋。
Dynamic programming, as you recall way back
动态编程，回想起来
before Thanksgiving, is a super exciting powerful technique
在感恩节之前，是一种非常令人兴奋的强大技术
to design algorithms, especially to solve optimization problems
设计算法，尤其是解决优化问题
where you want to maximize or minimize something.
您想最大化或最小化某物的地方。
Last time, we saw how two algorithms we already
上次，我们看到了两种算法
knew-- namely, how to compute the nth Fibonacci number
知道-即如何计算第n个斐波那契数
and how to compute shortest paths via Bellman-Ford--
以及如何通过Bellman-Ford计算最短路径-
are really dynamic programs in disguise.
是真正变相的动态程序。
And indeed for, at least for Bellman-Ford,
确实，至少对于贝尔曼·福特来说，
that's how they were invented, was
那是他们发明的方式
to apply a general technique which
应用通用技术
we're going to see today in full generality,
今天我们将全面了解
more or less-- most of this is generality--
或多或少-其中大部分是笼统性-
in five easy steps.
只需五个简单步骤。
And we're going to see that technique applied
我们将看到该技术的应用
to two new problems which are much more
两个新的问题
interesting than the ones we've already solved-- namely,
比我们已经解决的解决方案更有趣-
how to make your text look nice in a paragraph,
如何使您的文字在段落中看起来不错，
where to break the lines.
在哪里打破界限。
That's text justification.
那是文字上的理由。
And how to win and make loads of money at blackjack.
以及如何在二十一点赢钱并赚钱。
So lots of practical stuff here, and we're
这里有很多实用的东西，我们
going to see one new technique for
将会看到一种新技术
general dynamic programming.
通用动态编程。
These are some things I wrote last time.
这些是我上次写的东西。
Actually, one of them I didn't write last time.
实际上，我上次没有写过其中一个。
In general, you can think of dynamic programming
通常，您可以想到动态编程
as a carefully executed brute force search.
作为精心执行的蛮力搜索。
So in some sense, your algorithm is
所以从某种意义上说，您的算法是
going to be trying all the possibilities,
将尝试所有可能性，
but somehow avoiding the fact that there
但以某种方式避免了存在
are exponentially many of them.
数量成倍增加。
By thinking of it in a clever way,
通过巧妙的思考，
you can reduce the exponential search space
您可以减少指数搜索空间
down to a polynomial one, even though you're still
降为多项式，即使您仍然
not being very intelligent you're still blindly trying
不是很聪明，你还在盲目地尝试
all possibilities.
所有的可能性。
So that's the brute force part.
这就是蛮力部分。
In more detail, the three main techniques
更详细地说，三种主要技术
in dynamic programming are the idea of guessing, the idea
在动态编程中，是猜测的想法，
that, oh, I want to find the best way to solve a problem.
哦，我想找到解决问题的最佳方法。
Let's pick out some feature of the solution
让我们挑选解决方案的一些功能
that I want to know.
我想知道的
I don't know it, so I'll guess the answer--
我不知道，所以我猜答案-
meaning I'll try all the possibilities for that choice
意思是我会尝试所有可能的选择
and take the best one.
并选出最好的一个。
So guessing is really central to dynamic programming.
因此，猜测对于动态编程至关重要。
Then we also use a recursion, some way
然后我们还使用某种方式的递归
to express the solution to our problem in terms of solutions
用解决方案表达对我们问题的解决方案
to sub-problems.
子问题。
So it's usually very easy to get a recursion
所以通常很容易获得递归
for a lot of problems as long as they
只要有很多问题
have some kind of substructure.
具有某种子结构。
Like shortest paths, we had that some paths of shortest paths
像最短路径一样，我们有一些最短路径
were also shortest paths, so that was handy.
也是最短的路径，所以很方便。
Usually the recursion by itself is exponential time,
通常，递归本身就是指数时间，
like even with Fibonacci numbers.
甚至连斐波那契数也一样。
But we add in this technique of memoization,
但是我们添加了这种记忆技术，
which is just once we compute an answer we've stored in a lookup
这只是我们计算出存储在查询中的答案之后
table, if we ever need that answer again
表，如果我们再次需要该答案
we reuse it instead of recomputing it.
我们重用它而不是重新计算它。
So we store it.
因此，我们将其存储。
We write down in our memo pad anything that we compute.
我们在记事本中写下我们计算的任何内容。
Those techniques, all these techniques together
这些技术，所有这些技术加在一起
give you, typically, a polynomial time
通常为您提供多项式时间
dynamic program-- when they work, of course.
动态程序-当然可以。
Memoization makes the recursion polynomial time.
记忆使递归多项式时间变长。
The guessing is what is doing a brute force search.
猜测是在进行暴力搜索。
And magically, it all works if you're careful.
而且，神奇的是，如果您小心翼翼，一切都会奏效。
Another perspective-- kind of an orthogonal perspective
另一个视角-一种正交视角
or another way of thinking about it, which I think
或另一种思考方式，我认为
should be comfortable for you because we
应该让您感到舒适，因为我们
spent a lot of time doing shortest paths
花了很多时间做最短的路径
and expressing problems that we care about in terms of shortest
并用最短的时间表达我们关心的问题
paths even if they don't look like it at first glance--
路径，即使乍一看也不像，
dynamic programming in some sense
某种意义上的动态编程
is always computing shortest paths in a DAG.
总是在DAG中计算最短路径。
So you have some problem you want to solve,
所以您有一些要解决的问题，
like you have text you want to split up into lines so it looks
就像您要分割成几行的文本一样
nice in a paragraph, you express that problem somehow
一段很不错，您以某种方式表达了这个问题
as a directed acyclic graph.
作为有向无环图。
And then we know how to compute shortest path
然后我们知道如何计算最短路径
in directed acyclic graphs in linear time.
在线性时间的有向无环图中。
And that's basically what dynamic programming is doing.
这基本上就是动态编程正在做的事情。
I didn't realize this until last week,
直到上周我才意识到这一点，
so this is a new perspective.
所以这是一个新观点。
It's an experimental perspective.
这是实验性的观点。
But I think it's helpful.
但我认为这很有帮助。
It's actually-- dynamic programming is not that new.
实际上，动态编程并不是那么新。
It's all about how to be clever in setting up that DAG.
这是关于如何聪明地设置DAG的全部内容。
But in the end, the algorithm is very simple.
但是最后，该算法非常简单。
And then we had this other perspective--
然后我们有了另一种观点
back to this perspective, I guess.
回到这个角度，我猜。
In general, we have-- the real problem we want to solve,
总的来说，我们有-我们要解决的真正问题，
we generalize it in some sense by considering
我们在某种意义上通过考虑
lots of different sub-problems that we might care about.
许多我们可能关心的子问题。
Like with Fibonacci, we had the nth Fibonacci number.
与斐波那契一样，我们有第n个斐波那契数。
We really just wanted the nth Fibonacci number.
我们真的只想要第n个斐波那契数。
But along the way, we're going to compute all f1 up to fn.
但是在此过程中，我们将计算所有f1到fn。
So those are our sub-problems.
这些就是我们的子问题。
And if we compute the amount of time
如果我们计算时间量
we need to solve each sub-problem
我们需要解决每个子问题
and multiply that by the number of sub-problems we get,
并乘以我们得到的子问题的数量，
the total time required by the algorithm.
算法所需的总时间。
This is a general true fact.
这是一个普遍的真实事实。
And the fun part here is we get to treat any recursive calls
这里有趣的部分是我们可以处理任何递归调用
in this recursion as free, as constant time,
在此递归中，它是自由的，恒定的时间，
because we really only pay for it first time.
因为我们真的只是第一次付款。
That's counted out here.
在这里算出来。
The second time we call it, it's already memoized,
我们第二次称呼它已经被记住，
so we don't have to pay for it.
因此我们不必为此付费。
So this is, in some sense, an amortization,
因此，从某种意义上讲，这是摊销，
if you remember amortization from table doubling.
如果您还记得表加倍的摊销。
We're just changing around when we
我们只是在改变时
count the cost of each sub-problem,
计算每个子问题的成本，
and then this is the total running time.
这就是总的运行时间
OK, so that's the spirit we saw already.
好的，这就是我们已经看到的精神。
I'm going to give you the five general steps,
我将给您五个一般步骤，
and then we're going to apply them to two new problems.
然后我们将它们应用于两个新问题。
So five easy steps to dynamic programming.
因此，进行动态编程的五个简单步骤。
Unfortunately, these are not necessarily sequential steps.
不幸的是，这些不一定是顺序步骤。
They're a little bit interdependent,
它们有点相互依存，
and so "easy" should be in quotes.
因此，“ easy”应该用引号引起来。
This is how you would express a dynamic program,
这就是表达动态程序的方式，
and in some sense how you'd invent one,
从某种意义上讲，您将如何发明一个，
but in particular how you would explain one.
但特别是您将如何解释。
OK, let me get to the main steps first.
好的，让我先进入主要步骤。
First step is to figure out what your sub-problems are
第一步是弄清楚您的子问题是什么
going to be.
将。
Second part is to guess something.
第二部分是猜测。
Third step is to relate sub-problem solutions, usually
第三步通常是关联子问题解决方案
with a recurrence.
复发。
I guess always with a recurrence.
我猜总是会复发。
Fourth step is to actually build an algorithm.
第四步是实际构建算法。
And we saw two ways to do that last time.
我们上次看到了两种方法来做到这一点。
One is to use recursion and memoization, which
一种是使用递归和记忆，
is the way I like to think about it.
是我喜欢考虑的方式。
But if you prefer, you can follow the bottom up approach.
但是，如果您愿意，可以遵循自下而上的方法。
And usually that's called building a table.
通常，这称为建立表格。
And that one's basically to turn our recursion and memoization,
基本上是要改变我们的递归和记忆，
which is kind of fancy, into a bunch
有点花哨，成一堆
of for loops, which is pretty simple.
for循环，这非常简单。
And this is going to be more practical, faster, and so on.
这将更加实用，更快，等等。
And depending on your preference, one of them
根据您的喜好，其中之一
is more intuitive than the other.
比其他人更直观。
It doesn't matter.
没关系
They have the same running time, more or less,
它们或多或少具有相同的运行时间，
in the worst case.
在最坏的情况下。
Then the fifth step is to solve the original problem.
然后，第五步是解决原始问题。
All right, so we've sort of seen this before.
好吧，所以我们以前已经看到过这种情况。
In fact I have, over here, a convenient table.
实际上，我在这里有一张方便的桌子。
It's called cheating.
这就是所谓的作弊。
The two problems we saw last time, Fibonacci numbers
我们上次看到的两个问题，斐波那契数
and shortest paths.
和最短的路径。
And I've got steps one, two, three,
我已经完成了第一，第二，第三步，
four-- I ran out of room, so I didn't write five yet.
四个-我没房间了，所以我还没写五个。
But we'll get there.
但是我们会到达那里。
So what are our sub-problems?
那么我们的子问题是什么？
Well, for Fibonacci, they were f1 through fn.
好吧，对于斐波那契来说，他们是f1到fn。
So there were n different sub-problems.
因此，存在n个不同的子问题。
And in general because of this formula,
通常，由于这个公式，
we want to count how many sub-problems are there.
我们要计算那里有多少个子问题。
So number of sub-problems is-- this
所以子问题的数量是
is what we need to do algorithmically.
这是我们需要做的算法。
And then for analysis, we want to counter
然后为了分析，我们想对付
number of sub-problems for step one.
第一步的子问题数量。
And so for Fibonacci there were n of them.
因此，对于斐波那契来说，其中有n个。
For shortest paths, we defined this delta sub k of sv.
对于最短路径，我们定义了sv的delta sub k。
This was the shortest path from s
这是距离s的最短路径
to v they uses at most k edges.
到v，他们最多使用k个边。
That was sort of what Bellman-Ford was doing.
这就是贝尔曼·福特所做的事情。
And the number of different sub-problems
和不同的子问题数量
here was v squared, because we had to do this for every vertex
这是v平方的，因为我们必须对每个顶点执行此操作
v and we had to do it for every value of k between 0
v，我们必须对0之间的k的每个值执行此操作
and v minus 1. v minus was is the number of rounds
和v减1。v减是轮数
we need in Bellman-Ford.
我们需要贝尔曼福特公司。
So it's v times v, different sub-problems,
这是v乘以v，不同的子问题，
b squared of them.
b平方它们。
OK, second thing was we wanted to solve our problem.
好的，第二件事是我们想解决我们的问题。
And we do that by guessing some feature of the solution.
我们通过猜测解决方案的某些功能来做到这一点。
In Fibonacci, there was no guessing.
在斐波那契，没有猜测。
So the number of different choices for your guess is one.
因此，供您猜测的不同选择数是一个。
There's nothing.
什么也没有。
There's only one choice, which is to do nothing.
只有一种选择，就是什么都不做。
And for shortest paths, what we guessed was--
对于最短的路径，我们猜测是-
we know we're looking for some path from s v. B Let's guess
我们知道我们正在寻找s v。B的一些路径
what the last edge is.
最后的优势是什么。
There's some last edge from u to v,
从u到v还有最后一个优势，
assuming the path has more than one edge-- or more
假设路径具有多个边缘-或更多
than zero edges.
比零边缘。
When could the edge possibly be?
什么时候可能成为优势？
Well, it's some incoming edge to v.
好吧，这是v的一些优势。
So there's going to be indegree of v different choices
所以会有v个不同的选择
for that.
为了那个原因。
And to account for the case that that's zero, we do a plus 1.
考虑到零的情况，我们加一。
But that's not a big deal.
但这没什么大不了的。
So that was the number of different choices.
这就是不同选择的数量。
In general if we're going to guess something,
一般来说，如果我们要猜测一些东西，
we need to write down the number of choices.
我们需要写下选择的数量。
For the guess, how many different possibilities
猜测，有多少种不同的可能性
are there?
在那儿？
That's our analysis.
那就是我们的分析。
OK, the next thing is the recurrence.
好，接下来就是复发了。
That's step three.
那是第三步。
We want to relate all the sub-problem solutions
我们要关联所有子问题解决方案
to each other.
对彼此。
For Fibonacci, that's the definition
对于斐波那契，那就是定义
of Fibonacci numbers.
斐波那契数。
So it's really easy.
因此，这真的很容易。
For shortest paths, we wrote this min.
对于最短的路径，我们写了这个分钟。
In general, typically it's a min or a max,
通常，通常是最小值或最大值，
whatever you're trying to solve here.
无论您要在这里解决什么。
We're doing shortest paths.
我们正在做最短的路径。
You could do longest paths in the same way.
您可以用相同的方式做最长的路径。
So you compute them in of delta sub sk minus 1 of su.
因此，您用delta sub sk减去su 1来计算它们。
The idea is we want to compute this part of the path, the s
想法是我们要计算路径的这一部分s
to u part.
给你一部分。
And we know that has one fewer edge, because we just
而且我们知道这少了一点优势，因为我们只是
guessed what the last edge was.
猜到最后的优势是什么。
Except we don't really know what the last edge was,
除非我们真的不知道最后的优势是什么，
so we have to try them all.
所以我们必须全部尝试。
We try all the incoming edges into v-- that's this part--
我们将所有传入的边尝试成v-这就是这一部分-
and for each of them we compute--
我们为每个人计算-
I forgot something here.
我在这里忘记了一些东西。
This is the cost of the first part of the path.
这是路径第一部分的成本。
Then I also need to do plus the weight of the uv edge.
然后，我还需要加上uv边缘的重量。
That will be the total cost of that path.
那就是那条道路的总成本。
You add those up, you do it for every incoming edge.
您将这些累加起来，就可以对每个传入的边缘进行处理。
That is, in some sense, considering all possible paths.
也就是说，在某种意义上，考虑所有可能的路径。
Assuming you find the shortest path from s to u,
假设您找到了从s到u的最短路径，
that's going to be the best way to get there.
那将是到达那里的最好方法。
And then use some edge from u to v for some choice of u.
然后使用从u到v的边来选择u。
This will try all of them.
这将尝试所有这些。
So it's really trying all the possibilities.
因此，它确实在尝试所有可能性。
So it's pretty clear this is correct
所以很明显这是正确的
if there are no negative weight cycles.
如果没有负体重循环。
You have to prove some things.
你必须证明一些事情。
We've already proved them.
我们已经证明了它们。
It's just slow, but once you add memoization, it's fast.
这只是很慢，但是一旦添加了备忘录，它就会很快。
Now, how long does it take to evaluate this recurrence,
现在，评估这种复发需要多长时间，
constant time, if you don't count the recursive
固定时间，如果不计算递归
calls or count them as constant?
打电话还是算他们不变？
Over here, we're taking a min over n degree of v things.
在这里，我们要花最少的时间处理n个v事物。
So we have to pay n degree of v time,
因此，我们必须付出n倍的v时间，
again the recursions as free.
再次将递归视为免费。
But for each one of them, we have to do an addition.
但是对于其中每个，我们都必须做一个附加。
So it's constant work per guess.
因此，每个猜测都是不断的工作。
And this is quite common.
这很普遍。
Often, the number of guesses and the running time
通常，猜测次数和运行时间
per sub-problem are the same, the constant factors.
每个子问题都相同，是不变的因素。
Sometimes they're different.
有时它们是不同的。
We'll see some examples today.
今天我们将看到一些示例。
OK, step four.
好，第四步。
Let's see.
让我们来看看。
So here we evaluate the time per sub-problem.
因此，这里我们评估每个子问题的时间。
Once you have the recurrence, that becomes clear.
一旦复发，那就很清楚了。
You want to make sure that's polynomial.
您要确保它是多项式。
Often these are the same.
通常这些都是一样的。
And then we add the recursive memorize or build a DP table.
然后我们添加递归记忆或构建一个DP表。
I'm not going to write those.
我不会写那些。
We did it for Fibonacci last time, shortest paths.
我们上次为斐波那契做的是最短的路径。
Pretty easy.
相当容易。
And in general, what we need to check here
通常，我们需要在此处检查什么
is that the sub problem recurrence is acyclic.
子问题重复发生是非周期性的。
In other words, that it has a topological order so
换句话说，它具有拓扑顺序
we can use topological sort.
我们可以使用拓扑排序。
We don't actually use topological algorithm usually.
实际上，通常我们实际上并不使用拓扑算法。
You can just think about it.
您可以考虑一下。
In the case of Fibonacci numbers,
对于斐波那契数，
it's clear you want to start with the smallest one
很明显，您想从最小的一个开始
and end up with the biggest one.
并得到最大的一个。
You can't do the reverse, because then when
你不能做相反的事情，因为那时候
you're trying to computer the nth you don't have the ones
您正在尝试使用第n台计算机，而没有
you need, the n minus 1 and n minus 2.
您需要n减1和n减2。
But if you do it in this order, you always
但是，如果按此顺序执行操作，
have the one you need by the time you get there.
到达目的地时就拥有您需要的那个。
In general, there's a DAG there--
一般来说，那里有一个DAG
and for Fibonacci, it was like this.
对斐波那契来说，就是这样。
Every node depends on the previous
每个节点都取决于前一个
and the second previous.
和第二个。
But you just choose a topological order,
但是您只需选择一个拓扑顺序，
which is here left to right, and you're golden.
从左到右，这是您的黄金。
And these are actually the for loops
这些实际上是for循环
you get in the bottom of DP.
您进入了DP的底部。
For shortest paths, you have to think a little bit.
对于最短的路径，您必须考虑一下。
You have to do the for loop over k on the outside,
您必须在外部对k进行for循环，
the for loop over V on the inside.
内部的V上的for循环。
The reverse does not work.
反之则不起作用。
I won't go through that, but we drew the DAG last time.
我不会讲这个，但是上次我们画了DAG。
And that's the main thing you need to do here.
这就是您在这里要做的主要事情。
And then, of course, you use this formula
然后，当然，您可以使用以下公式
to compute the overall running time, which is just multiplying
计算总的运行时间，这只是相乘
this quantity with this quantity.
这个数量与此数量。
Total time.
总时间。
Then there's just one last step that
然后只有最后一步
usually isn't that big a deal, but you have think about it.
通常没什么大不了的，但是您已经考虑过了。
You need to make sure that the problem you actually
您需要确保您实际遇到的问题
cared about solving gets solved.
关心解决就解决了。
In the case of Fibonacci and shortest paths,
对于斐波那契和最短路径，
this is pretty clear.
这很清楚。
I didn't write it.
我没写
We can do it on here.
我们可以在这里做。
Solve the original problem.
解决原来的问题。
Fibonaci, it is Fn.
斐波那契，是Fn。
And this is one of our sub-problems,
这是我们的子问题之一，
so if we solve all of them, we're done.
因此，如果我们解决所有问题，我们就完成了。
For shortest paths, it's basically
对于最短的路径，基本上
delta sub v minus 1 of sv for all v. That's
所有v的delta sub v减去sv的1。
single source shortest paths.
单源最短路径。
And by our Bellman-Ford analysis,
根据我们的Bellman-Ford分析，
that gives us the right shortest paths.
这给了我们正确的最短路径。
There are no negative weight cycles.
没有负重量循环。
And sometimes this requires extra time
有时这需要额外的时间
to combine your solutions to get the real thing.
结合您的解决方案以获得真实的东西。
Here of course, we just have the answers, so writing them down
当然，在这里，我们只有答案，所以写下来
does not take very long.
不需要很长时间。
So that's the dominant running time-- which I didn't write,
这就是主要的运行时间-我没有写，
I should have written in under for here-- this ends up
我应该在下面写下来-这最终
being n, this ends up being VE.
为n，则最终为VE。
OK, I don't want to spend more time on those examples.
好的，我不想在这些示例上花费更多的时间。
Let's go to new things.
让我们去看看新事物。
So first problem we're going to look at today
所以第一个问题我们今天要看
is text justification.
是文本对齐。
And the informal statement of this problem
关于这个问题的非正式陈述
is you're given some text-- which
给你一些文字吗？
means a string, a whole bunch of characters.
表示字符串，一串完整的字符。
And we want to split them into good lines.
我们希望将它们划分为好线。
The rules of the game here are we're going to,
我们将要遵循的游戏规则
like in the early lectures of document distance
就像早期文件距离讲座
where you have some definition of splitting
您对拆分有一些定义
a document into words separated by spaces.
将文档分成用空格隔开的单词。
And what we want to do is cut.
而我们要做的就是削减。
We can only cut between word boundaries.
我们只能在单词边界之间切换。
And we want to write some text, it's
我们想写一些文字，
going to have some spaces in it.
里面会有一些空间。
Then there's a new line, something like that.
然后有一个新行，像这样。
And we want to justify our text on the right here.
我们想在这里证明我们的文字正确。
And so we'd like to avoid big gaps like this because they
因此，我们希望避免这样的巨大差距，因为它们
look ugly, they're hard to read.
看起来很丑，很难看。
Now, if you use Microsoft Word-- at least
现在，如果您使用Microsoft Word，至少
before the latest versions-- they
在最新版本之前-他们
follow a greedy strategy, which is very simple.
遵循贪婪的策略，这很简单。
You pack as many words as you can on the first line,
您可以在第一行尽可能多地打包单词，
then you go to the next line, pack as many words
然后您转到下一行，打包尽可能多的单词
as you can on the second line.
就像您在第二行一样
Keep going like that.
继续这样下去。
And that strategy is not optimal.
而且这种策略不是最佳的。
If you use LaTeX-- as some of you
如果您使用LaTeX--
have been doing on problem sets, and I think also new versions
一直在做问题集，我想也是新版本
of Word but I'm not sure-- then it
Word，但我不确定-那么
uses dynamic programming to solve this problem.
使用动态编程来解决此问题。
And that's what we're going to do here.
这就是我们在这里要做的。
So let me specify a little bit more about what we mean here.
因此，让我再详细说明一下我们的意思。
So the text we're going to think of as a list of words.
因此，我们将文本视为单词列表。
And we're going to define a quantity badness.
我们将定义数量缺陷。
And this is an anesthetic quantity, if you will.
如果您愿意，这是麻醉药。
I'm going to tell you what LaTeX uses.
我将告诉您LaTeX的用途。
But this is sort of how bad it is
但这有点糟
to use-- or let's say, yeah, words i through j as a line.
使用-或者说，是的，将i到j作为一行。
So this is python notation.
所以这是python表示法。
So it starts at i and ends at J minus 1.
因此，它从i开始，到J减去1。
That'll be convenient.
那会很方便。
So I have this list of words.
所以我有这个词表。
And if I look at words i through j minus 1
如果我看单词i到j减1
and I think of what happens if I pack them in a line, well,
我想如果我把它们打包成一行会发生什么，
they may fit or they may not fit.
他们可能适合或他们可能不适合。
So there are going to be two cases.
因此，将有两种情况。
If they don't fit, I'm going to write infinity.
如果它们不合适，我将写无穷大。
So that's really bad.
所以那真的很糟糕。
So I have some notion of how wide my line can be.
因此，我对我的业务范围有一定的了解。
And if the sum of the lengths of those words plus the sum
如果这些单词的长度之和加上
of the lengths of the spaces as small as possible
间距的长度应尽可能小
is bigger than the width of my screen-- or page,
大于屏幕或页面的宽度，
I guess-- then I say they don't fit,
我想-然后我说它们不合适
and then I define badness to be infinity-- meaning,
然后我将不良定义为无穷大-意思是，
I never want to do that.
我永远都不想那样做。
This is actually LaTeX sloppy mode,
这实际上是LaTeX的草率模式，
if you want to be technical.
如果您想成为技术专家。
Otherwise, it's going to be page width minus total width cubed.
否则，它将是页面宽度减去总宽度。
Why cubed?
为什么要立方体？
Who knows.
谁知道。
This is the LaTeX rule.
这是LaTeX规则。
And squared would probably also be fine.
平方也可能很好。
So this is the width of the page minus the total width
所以这是页面的宽度减去总宽度
of those words, which you also have
这些话中，你也有
to include the spaces here.
在这里包括空格。
You take the difference.
你差价了。
You cube it.
你把它立方体。
And so when this is small-- I mean,
所以，当这很小的时候，我是说，
when these are very close-- then this
当这些非常接近时-那么
is going to be close to zero.
将接近零。
That's good.
那很好。
That means you use most of the line.
这意味着您将使用大部分线路。
When the total width is much smaller than the page width,
当总宽度远小于页面宽度时，
then this will be a large value.
那么这将是一个很大的价值。
You cube it, it will be even larger.
您将其立方体化，它将更大。
So this will highly discourage big gaps like this.
因此，这将极大地阻止类似的巨大差距。
And it will very much discourage not fitting.
这将极大地阻止不适合的人。
So there's a tradeoff, of course.
因此，当然要进行权衡。
And the idea is you might-- in the greedy algorithm,
想法是，您可能会在贪婪算法中
you make the first line as good as you can.
您会尽力做好第一行。
But it might actually be better to leave out
但实际上将其省略可能会更好
some of the words that would fit here
一些适合这里的词
in order to make the next line better.
为了使下一行更好。
In general, it's hard to tell, where should I
一般来说，很难告诉我应该在哪里
cut the lines in order to get the best overall strategy?
为了获得最佳整体策略而削减界限？
What I'd like to minimize is the sum
我想最小化的是总和
of the badnesses of the lines.
的缺点。
So it's a sum of cubes, and that's really hard
所以这是一个立方体的总和，这真的很难
to think about.
想一下。
But that's what dynamic programming is for.
但这就是动态编程的目的。
You don't have to think.
您不必思考。
It's great because it's brute force.
很棒，因为它是蛮力的。
OK, so the first thing we need to do is define sub-problems.
好的，所以我们要做的第一件事是定义子问题。
This is, in some sense, the hard part.
从某种意义上讲，这是最困难的部分。
The rest will follow easily.
其余的将很容易理解。
So I think actually it might be easier
所以我认为实际上可能会更容易
to think about, for this problem, what
考虑这个问题
would be the brute force strategy?
会是蛮力策略吗？
How would you try all possibilities, exponential
您将如何尝试所有可能性，指数
time?
时间？
Suggestions?
有什么建议吗？
Yeah?
是啊
AUDIENCE: Try all partitions of the words that don't fit?
听众：尝试对所有不合适的单词进行分区吗？
PROFESSOR: Try all partitions of the word,
教授：请尝试单词的所有分区，
so-- of the string of words.
等等。
So I mean, it could be it all fits in on one line.
所以我的意思是，这可能全都适合。
It could be it's split into two lines.
可能分为两行。
I try all possible splits there.
我在那里尝试所有可能的分割。
In general, I'm guessing for every word,
总的来说，我猜每个字，
does this start a line or not?
这是否开始行？
That would be all ways.
那将是所有方式。
And so there are 2 to the n.
因此，n等于2。
If I have n words, there's 2 to the n different splits.
如果我有n个单词，则n个不同的拆分为2。
For every word I say yes or no, does this is begin a line?
对于我说的每个单词，是或否，这是一行吗？
So what I'd like to figure out is where those lines begin.
所以我想弄清楚的是这些行的起点。
That was the point of that exercise.
这就是该练习的重点。
So any suggestions?
有什么建议吗？
Maybe it's actually easier to jump ahead and think,
也许实际上前进起来会更容易，
what would I guess in my solution
我在解决方案中会猜到什么
if I have this big string of words?
如果我有这么大的字眼？
What's the natural first thing to guess?
首先要猜测的自然是什么？
Yeah?
是啊
AUDIENCE: Guess how long the first line is?
听众：猜猜第一行有多长时间？
PROFESSOR: Guess how long the first line is, yeah.
教授：猜猜第一行有多长时间。
We know that the first word begins a line.
我们知道第一个单词以一行开头。
But where does the second line begin?
但是第二行从哪里开始？
So I'd like to guess where the second line begins.
所以我想猜测第二行的开始位置。
That's-- so you know, I have the beginning of a line here
那是-所以你知道，我在这里有一行的开始
and then I have a beginning of a line here at the fourth word.
然后我在第四个单词的第一个行开始。
Where does the second line begin?
第二行从哪里开始？
I don't know.
我不知道。
Guess.
猜测。
So I'm going to try all the possible words
所以我将尝试所有可能的单词
after the first word.
在第一个字之后。
And say, well, what if I started my second line here?
然后说，好吧，如果我在这里开始第二行呢？
At some point I'm going to be packing
在某个时候，我要打包
too much into the first line, and so I abort.
第一行太多，所以我放弃了。
But I'll try them all.
但我会全部尝试。
Why not?
为什么不？
OK, that's good.
好那很好
The issue is that once I've chosen
问题是，一旦我选择了
where the second line is, of course the next thing I want
第二行在哪里，当然是我想要的下一件事
to guess is where the third line begins.
猜猜是第三行开始的地方。
And then I want I guess where the fourth line begins,
然后我想我猜第四行从哪里开始
and so on.
等等。
In general, I need to set up my sub-problems
通常，我需要设置我的子问题
so that after I do the first guess
这样我做第一个猜测之后
I have the problem of the original type.
我有原始类型的问题。
So originally I have all the words.
所以原来我有所有的话。
But after I guess where the second line begins,
但是我猜到第二行的开始
I have the remaining words.
我还有剩下的话。
What's a good word for the remaining words?
剩下的单词有什么好词？
If I give you a list of words and I want from here on,
如果我给你一个单词列表，我想从这里开始，
it's called-- what?
叫做-什么？
A sub-problem, yes.
一个子问题，是的。
That's what we want to define.
那就是我们要定义的。
It's called a suffix of the array.
它称为数组的后缀。
That's the word I was looking for.
那就是我要找的词。
It's tough when I only have one word answers.
当我只有一个单词的答案时，这很难。
So my sub-problems are going to be suffixes.
因此，我的子问题将是后缀。
Which is, in python notation, i colon.
用python表示法是冒号。
They call it splices.
他们称其为拼接。
And how many sub-problems are there if I have n words?
如果我有n个单词，有多少个子问题？
Two?
二？
Sorry?
抱歉？
AUDIENCE: 2 to the n.
听众：2到n。
PROFESSOR: 2 the n?
教授：2个n？
That would be a problem if it's 2 to the n.
如果它是2到n，那将是一个问题。
I hope it's only n.
我希望只有n。
Originally, we said, OK, for every word, we're going to say,
最初，我们说，好吧，我们要说的每个字，
is this in our out?
这是我们的吗？
Is this the beginning or not?
这是开始吗？
That's 2 to the n.
那是2到n。
But here, the idea is we're only thinking about, well,
但是这里的想法是，我们只是在考虑，
what are the words that remain?
剩下的词是什么？
And it could be you've dealt with the first 100 words
可能是您已经处理了前100个字
and then you've got n minus 100 left,
然后剩下n减100，
or it could be you've dealt with the first thousand words
或者可能是您已经处理了前一千个单词
and you've got n minus 1,000.
而您的n减为1,000。
There's only n choices for that.
只有n种选择。
We're only remembering one line, this is the key.
我们只记得一行，这是关键。
Even though we may have already guessed several lines,
即使我们可能已经猜到了几行，
we're just going to remember, well, OK.
我们只是要记住，好吧。
This is what we have left to do.
这就是我们要做的。
So let's forget about the past.
因此，让我们忘记过去。
This is what makes dynamic programming efficient.
这就是使动态编程高效的原因。
And we're just going to solve it, solve these sub-problems,
我们将要解决它，解决这些子问题，
forgetting about the past.
忘记过去。
So the sub-problem-- I'm not going
所以子问题-我不去
to write it here-- is if I give you these words,
在这里写-如果我给你这些话，
never mind the other words, how do I pack them optimally
没关系，我该如何最佳包装
into a paragraph?
变成一段？
I don't care about the other words, just these words.
我不在乎这些词，只在乎这些词。
So this is a different version of the same problem.
因此，这是同一问题的不同版本。
Initially, we have n words to do.
最初，我们有n个单词要做。
Now I have n minus i words to do.
现在我有n减i字要做。
But it's again text justification.
但这又是文本理由。
I want to solve this problem on those words.
我想用这些话解决这个问题。
That's just how I'm going to define it.
这就是我要定义它的方式。
This will work if I can specify a recurrence relation.
如果我可以指定递归关系，这将起作用。
As we said, what we guess is where
正如我们所说，我们猜测是在哪里
to break the first line, where to start
打破第一行，从哪里开始
the second line for those words.
这些词的第二行。
OK, so this is-- it could be the i plus first line.
好的，这是-可能是i加第一行。
It could be the i plus second line-- or sorry, word.
可能是i加第二行，或者抱歉。
Some word after i is where we guess the second word.
我之后的一些词是我们猜出第二个词的地方。
The number of choices for the guess is at most n minus i.
猜测的选择数最多为n减去i。
I'm just going to think of that as order n.
我只是将其视为n阶。
It won't matter.
没关系
The third part is we need a recurrence relation.
第三部分是我们需要一个递归关系。
I claim this is very easy.
我声称这很容易。
I'm going to-- I didn't give this problem a name,
我要-我没有给这个问题起个名字，
so I'm just going to write it as DP of i.
所以我只是将其写为i的DP。
So this is going to be the solution to that suffix, words
所以这将是该后缀的解决方案
from i onward.
从我开始。
And I'd like to-- what I want to do
我想-我想做什么
is consider all possible guesses.
考虑所有可能的猜测。
So I mean this is going to be pretty formulaic at this point.
因此，我的意思是，这将是非常明确的公式。
After I've set up these ideas there's pretty much
设定好这些想法之后，
only one thing I can write here, which
我只能在这里写一件事
is I want to do a for loop.
我想做一个for循环。
That would be the for loop of where
那是for循环的地方
the second line can start.
第二行可以开始。
I can't start at i, because that's
我不能从我开始，因为那是
where the first line starts.
第一行开始的地方。
But it could start at i plus 1.
但这可以从我加1开始。
And this special value of n will mean
n的特殊值意味着
that there is no second line.
没有第二行。
OK, so DP of i-- now I want to do this for loop
好的，所以我的DP –现在我要进行循环
in order to try all the possible guesses.
为了尝试所有可能的猜测。
j will be the word where the next thing starts.
j将是下一个事物开始的词。
So then what do I write up here?
那我在这里写些什么呢？
If I make this guess-- all right, so I have word
如果我做出这个猜测-好吧，我有话要说
i is the first word of the first line.
我是第一行的第一个字。
And then word j is the first word of the second line.
然后单词j是第二行的第一个单词。
And then there's more stuff down below.
然后，下面还有更多内容。
I don't know what that is.
我不知道那是什么
But how can I use recursion to specify this?
但是如何使用递归来指定呢？
DP of j, exactly.
j的DP。
I guess if I'm doing recursion, I
我想我是否要进行递归，
should use parentheses instead of brackets.
应该使用括号而不是括号。
But if you're doing it bottom up,
但是，如果您是自下而上地做，
it would be square brackets.
这将是方括号。
So that's just DP of j.
这就是j的DP。
That's the cost of the rest of the problem.
那就是剩下的问题的代价。
And I can assume that that's free to compute.
我可以假设这是免费的。
This is the magic of dynamic programming.
这是动态编程的魔力。
But then I also have to think about, well,
但是，我还必须考虑一下，
what about the first line?
第一行呢？
How much does that cost?
费用多少？
Well, that's just badness of ij.
好吧，这只是ij的缺点。
And we've already defined that.
我们已经定义了这一点。
We can compute it in constant time.
我们可以在恒定时间内进行计算。
Dynamic programming doesn't really care what this is.
动态编程并不真正在乎这是什么。
It could be anything.
可能是任何东西。
As long as you're trying to minimize
只要您要尽量减少
the sum of the badnesses, whatever function is in here,
缺点的总和，无论这里有什么功能，
we just compute it here.
我们只是在这里计算。
That's the power of dynamic programming.
这就是动态编程的力量。
It works for all variations of this problem,
它适用于此问题的所有变体，
however you define badness.
但是，您定义不良。
So you might say, oh, that's a weird definition.
所以您可能会说，哦，这是一个奇怪的定义。
I want to use something else instead.
我想改用其他东西。
That's fine, as long as you can compute it
只要可以计算就可以了
in terms of just i and j and looking at those words.
就我和j而言，看着那些词。
OK, now I need to do a min over the whole thing.
好的，现在我需要对整个过程进行一分钟的处理。
So I want to minimize the sum of the badnesses.
因此，我想将弊端的总和最小化。
So I compute for every guess of j,
所以我计算出j的每个猜测
I compute the cost of the rest of the problem
我计算其余问题的成本
plus the cost of that first line.
加上第一行的费用。
And this, is in some sense, checking all possible solutions
从某种意义上讲，这是在检查所有可能的解决方案
magically.
神奇地。
OK.
好。
That's the recurrence.
这就是复发。
We need to check some things.
我们需要检查一些事情。
I guess right now we just want to compute how much time does
我想现在我们只想计算多少时间
this cost, time per sub-problem.
这个成本，每个子问题的时间。
To do this for loop, basically I do constant work-- all of this
为了进行循环，基本上我会不断工作-所有这些
is constant work-- for each choice.
持续不断的工作-每个选择。
So there's order n choices, so this is order n.
因此，有n个选择，这就是n个。
Now we have to check that there's
现在我们要检查
a topological order for this problem
此问题的拓扑顺序
or for these sub-problems.
或针对这些子问题。
And this is easy, but a little different
这很容易，但是有些不同
from what we've done before because we
从我们之前所做的事情开始，因为我们
have to actually work from the end backwards,
必须从头到尾真正地工作，
because we're expressing DP of i in terms
因为我们用i表示DP
of DP of larger values of i.
i的较大DP的乘积。
j is always bigger than i.
j总是比i大。
And so we have to do it from the right end back
所以我们必须从正确的末端开始
to the beginning.
一开始
And n minus 1 down to 0.
n减1降至0。
I didn't actually define DP of n.
我实际上没有定义DP的n。
There's a base case here which is DP of n equals 0.
这里有一个基本情况，即n的DP等于0。
Because the meaning of DP of n is I have zero words,
因为n的DP的含义是我有零个单词，
the nth word onward.
从第n个字开始。
There is no nth word.
没有第n个字。
It's 0 to n minus 1 in this notation.
在此符号中，它是0到n减去1。
So I don't pay anything for a blank line.
因此，我不需要为空白行支付任何费用。
OK, so that's our top logical order.
好的，这是我们的首要逻辑顺序。
This one, of course, is instantaneous.
当然，这是瞬时的。
And then we work backwards.
然后我们倒退。
And always whenever we need to compute something,
而且总是在每当我们需要计算某些东西时，
we already have the value.
我们已经拥有了价值。
The total time we get is going to be
我们得到的总时间将是
the number of sub problems-- which
子问题的数量-
is n times the running time per sub-problem.
是每个子问题的运行时间的n倍。
which is order n, which is order n squared.
这是n阶，这是n阶的平方。
And in the worst case, it is indeed theta n squared.
在最坏的情况下，它的确是平方。
Although in practice it's going to work better, because lines
尽管实际上它会更好地工作，因为线条
can't be too long.
不能太长。
So that's the running time.
这就是运行时间。
Then finally we have to check that the original problem
最后，我们必须检查原始问题
actually gets solved.
实际上得到解决。
And in this case, the original problem we need to solve
在这种情况下，我们需要解决的原始问题
is DP of 0 because DP of 0 means I take words from 0 onwards.
DP为0，因为DP为0表示我从0开始接受单词。
That's everybody.
那就是每个人。
So that's the actual problem I want to solve.
这就是我要解决的实际问题。
So we work backwards.
所以我们倒退了。
We solve all these sub-problems that we don't directly
我们解决了所有这些我们不直接解决的子问题
care about, but then the first one is the one we want.
关心，但是第一个就是我们想要的那个。
And we're done.
我们完成了。
So in quadratic time, we can find the best way
所以在二次时代，我们可以找到最好的方法
to pack words into lines.
将单词打包成行。
Question?
题？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
PROFESSOR: DP of j is returning.
教授：j的DP正在返回。
It's like this.
就像这样。
So DP of-- this is a recursive definition.
因此，DP的-是递归定义。
Imagine this is a recursive function.
想象一下这是一个递归函数。
I wrote equals, which is Haskell notation, if you will.
如果可以的话，我写了等于，这是Haskell表示法。
But normally, you think of this as like def DP of i
但是通常，您认为这就像我的def DP
is return min of this.
是此值的返回最小值。
This is python.
这是python。
So it's returning the cost.
因此，它正在退还成本。
What was the best way to pack those lines from j onwards?
从j开始打包这些行的最佳方法是什么？
That's what DP of j returns.
这就是j的DP返回。
So it's a number.
这是一个数字。
It's going to be a sum of badness values.
这将是不良值的总和。
Then we add on one new badness value.
然后，我们添加一个新的不良值。
It's still a sum of badness values.
它仍然是不良值的总和。
We return the best one that we find.
我们返回找到的最好的一个。
Now, this does not actually pack the words.
现在，这实际上并没有包含这些单词。
That's a good-- maybe your implicit question.
很好-也许是您的隐含问题。
It's not telling you how to pack the words.
它不是在告诉您如何打包单词。
It's telling you how much it costs to pack the words.
它告诉您打包单词的费用。
This is a lot like shortest paths where we didn't-- it was
这很像我们没有的最短路径-
annoying to actually figure out what the shortest path was.
实际找出最短路径是很烦的。
Not that annoying, but that's not
没那么烦人，但这不是
what we were usually aiming to do.
我们通常打算做什么。
We were just trying to figure out the shortest path weight.
我们只是试图找出最短的路径权重。
And then once we knew the shortest path weight,
然后，一旦我们知道最短路径权重，
it was pretty easy to reconstruct the paths.
重建路径非常容易。
So maybe I'll take a little diversion to that
所以也许我会转移一点
and talk about parent pointers.
并讨论父指针。
The idea with parent pointers is just
父指针的想法仅仅是
remember which guess was best.
记住哪个猜测是最好的。
it's a very simple idea, but it applies to all dynamic programs
这是一个非常简单的想法，但它适用于所有动态程序
and lets you find the actual solution, not just
并让您找到实际的解决方案，而不仅仅是
the cost of the solution.
解决方案的成本。
We did the same thing with shortest paths.
我们用最短的路径做了同样的事情。
We even called them parent.
我们甚至称他们为父母。
So when we compute this min, were trying all choices of j.
因此，当我们计算此最小值时，正在尝试j的所有选择。
One of them-- or maybe more than one, but at least one of them
其中之一-或可能不止一个，但至少其中之一
actually gave you the min.
实际上给了你分钟。
That's usually called the arg min in mathematics.
在数学中通常称为arg min。
It's what was the value of j that gave you
是j给你的价值是什么
the minimum value of this thing.
这东西的最小值。
So I mean, when you compute the min,
所以我的意思是，当您计算最小值时，
you're iterating over every single one.
您正在遍历每一个。
Just keep track of which one was the best.
只要跟踪哪个是最好的。
That's it.
而已。
Call that the parent pointer.
称其为父指针。
Do I need to write that?
我需要写那个吗？
Here, parent-- parent of i is going
在这里，父母-我的父母要去
to be arg min of that same thing.
是同一件事的arg分钟。
So it's a j value.
所以这是aj值。
It's the best j value for i.
这是i的最佳j值。
And so we store that for each i.
因此，我们为每个i存储它。
It cost no more work, just a constant factor
它无需花费更多的工作，只是一个恒定的因素
more work than computing the min.
比计算最小值需要更多的工作。
We also write down the arg min.
我们还写下了arg分钟。
So we're already storing the min in the DP table.
因此，我们已经将最小值存储在DP表中。
DP of i would get sorted to be that.
我的DP将被排序为那样。
We also store parent of i.
我们还存储i的父项。
And then once we're done, we start with our original problem
然后，一旦完成，我们就从最初的问题开始
and we follow parent pointers to figure out
然后按照父指针找出
what the best choices were.
最好的选择是什么。
So we start at 0 because we know word zero begins a line.
因此我们从0开始，因为我们知道单词零开始一行。
And then 0 will be the first line.
然后0将是第一行。
Then we go to parent of 0.
然后我们转到0的父级。
That will be where the second line begins.
那就是第二行的开始。
Then we go to parent of parent of 0.
然后我们转到0的父级的父级。
That will be where the third line begins.
那就是第三行的开始。
OK, because these were the best choices
好，因为这些是最好的选择
for where the second line begins,
第二行开始的地方
this is the best place where the second line begins.
这是第二行开始的最佳位置。
Given that this is the first line,
鉴于这是第一行，
this is the best line where the second line begins
这是第二行开始的最佳行
given that this was the first line.
鉴于这是第一行。
So that's really the third line given this was the second line.
因此，这实际上是第三行，因为这是第二行。
Little confusing, but you just a simple for loop.
有点混乱，但是您只是一个简单的for循环。
You start with 0 because that's our original problem.
您从0开始，因为这是我们的原始问题。
You keep calling parent of the thing you currently have.
您一直称呼您当前拥有的东西的父母。
In linear time, you will reconstruct
在线性时间内，您将重建
where the lines break.
断线的地方。
So you can use this technique in any DP.
因此，您可以在任何DP中使用此技术。
It's very simple.
非常简单
It's totally automatic.
这是完全自动的。
Just like memoization is a technique
就像记忆是一种技术
that you can apply without thinking,
你可以不用考虑就可以申请
you could even write a program, given a recursive algorithm,
给定递归算法，您甚至可以编写程序，
would turn into a memorized recursive algorithm.
会变成一个记忆式递归算法。
It's totally automated.
它是完全自动化的。
Same thing with the bottom up DP table.
自下而上的DP表也是如此。
As long as you know what the topological order is,
只要您知道拓扑顺序是什么，
just make those for loops and then put
只是让那些for循环，然后把
exactly the recursive call but turn it into an array call.
完全递归调用，但将其转换为数组调用。
Boom, you've got a bottom up algorithm.
繁荣，您有一个自下而上的算法。
Totally automatic, no thinking required.
全自动，无需思考。
Parent pointers also, no thinking required.
父指针也，不需要思考。
As long as you're following the structure of trial guesses
只要您遵循试验猜测的结构
compute some value-- just remember
计算一些价值-请记住
what the guess was-- you reconstruct your solution.
猜测是什么-您可以重建解决方案。
That's the great thing about dynamic programming
这是动态编程的伟大之处
is how much of it is automatic.
是多少是自动的。
The hard part is figuring out what to guess
困难的部分是弄清楚猜出什么
and then what your sub-problems are, or the other order.
然后是您的子问题，或其他顺序。
Whatever works.
无论如何。
Any other questions about text?
关于文字还有其他问题吗？
I would like to move on to blackjack.
我想继续玩二十一点。
OK, now I brought some cards, because some of you
好，现在我带了一些卡，因为你们中的一些人
may not know the rules to blackjack.
可能不知道二十一点的规则。
How many people know blackjack?
有多少人知道二十一点？
OK.
好。
How many people do not and are willing to admit it?
有多少人不愿意接受呢？
A few, all right.
几个，好吧。
So this is for you and for fun, entertainment.
因此，这既适合您，也适合娱乐。
So I'm going to bring Victor up to help demonstrate
所以我要带维克多来帮助演示
the rules of blackjack.
二十一点的规则。
We're going to play standard Casino blackjack
我们将玩标准的赌场二十一点
as in the movie 21, or whatever.
就像电影21一样
So I'm going to just do a random cut here so I can't sheet.
因此，我将在这里进行随机切割，以致无法覆盖。
You have a tablet, that's scary.
你有平板电脑，那太可怕了。
You're going to look at strategy.
您将要研究策略。
VICTOR: Nothing special.
胜利者：没什么特别的。
PROFESSOR: All right.
教授：好的。
Hopefully you do not have x-ray vision.
希望您没有X光检查。
So the way it works is there's a dealer
所以它的运作方式是有经销商
player and one or more players.
玩家和一个或多个玩家。
We're just going to do it with one player to keep it simple.
为了使操作简单，我们只需要和一个玩家一起做即可。
I'm going to be the dealer.
我将成为经销商。
So my strategy is actually totally deterministic,
所以我的策略实际上是完全确定性的
there's nothing interesting.
没有什么有趣的。
Victor has the hard part of winning.
维克多（Victor）难以取胜。
So to start out, I believe we deal to you first, then
因此，一开始，我相信我们会先与您联系，然后
to me, then to you, then to me.
给我，然后给你，然后给我。
So let's hold up these cards, Victor,
Victor，让我们举起这些卡片，
so that people can see them.
这样人们才能看到它们。
You don't get to see one of my cards.
您看不到我的一张卡片。
That's some peculiarity of the rule.
这是该规则的特殊之处。
And if the sum of our cards goes over 21, we lose the game.
而且，如果我们的卡牌总和超过21，我们就会输掉比赛。
Victor first.
维克多第一。
I cannot have a value more than 21 in these hands,
这些手的价值不能超过21，
because I only have two cards.
因为我只有两张卡。
You have a value of-- ha, ace.
您的价值-哈哈，王牌。
Great.
大。
An ace can be a 1 or an 11.
ace可以是1或11。
That's the fun rule.
那是有趣的规则。
So this is either an 8 or an 18.
所以这是8或18。
And so Victor has a choice of whether to take another card
所以Victor可以选择是否要再拿一张卡
or not.
或不。
What would you like to do?
你想干什么？
VICTOR: Standard strategy says stand.
胜利者：标准策略表示立场。
PROFESSOR: He stands.
教授：他站着。
So he's going to stick to that.
因此，他将坚持这一点。
At this point, my cards flip over.
此时，我的卡片翻转了。
I have 17, which is same you, which
我有17岁，与您相同
I believe means-- I forget about tie rules.
我相信手段-我忘记了平局规则。
VICTOR: I have 18.
威克多：我有18岁。
PROFESSOR: You have 18.
教授：您有18岁。
All right.
好吧。
VICTOR: See?
胜利者：看到了吗？
The strategy works.
该策略有效。
PROFESSOR: So that's good.
教授：那很好。
I'm going to hit in the hope that I have a small card that
我要击中希望我有一张小卡片
will push me right above you.
会把我推到你的上方。
But I do not.
但我不。
I lose.
我输了。
I'm sad.
我伤心。
VICTOR: It says always stand on a 17.
威克多：它说总是站在17岁。
PROFESSOR: Oh, always stand on 17?
教授：哦，总是站在17岁吗？
Huh.
嗯
All right, never mind.
好吧，没关系。
Thanks.
谢谢。
Yeah, I still lose.
是的，我仍然输。
The game is over.
游戏结束了。
My strategy is always stand on a value--
我的策略始终立足于价值观
VICTOR: Stand on 17.
胜利者：站在17。
PROFESSOR: 17 or higher.
教授：17岁或以上。
And if I have a value less than 17, I always take another card.
如果我的价值小于17，我总是拿另一张卡。
So let's do it one more time to get it right.
因此，让我们再做一次以使其正确。
So I'm going to deal to you, deal to me, deal to you,
所以我要对付你，对付我，对付你，
deal to me.
给我。
So hold up your cards.
因此，举起您的卡片。
You have 18 again.
您又有18个。
Are you cheating?
你在作弊吗？
VICTOR: I still have to stand.
威克多：我还是得站起来。
PROFESSOR: You still stand, according to tablet.
教授：根据平板电脑，您仍然站着。
So I, in this case, have a 20.
因此，在这种情况下，我有20。
And so this I win.
因此，我赢了。
So you get the idea.
这样您就知道了。
Let's say in each case we're betting $1.
假设在每种情况下，我们都下注$ 1。
So at this point, we'd be even.
因此，在这一点上，我们将保持平衡。
He won $1, I won $1.
他赢了1美元，我赢了1美元。
But in general, slight-- I think it's balanced.
但总的来说，轻微-我认为它是平衡的。
VICTOR: For these rules, there's a 1% advantage for the house.
胜利者：按照这些规则，这所房子的优势为1％。
PROFESSOR: 1% advantage for the house.
教授：房子的优势为1％。
Interesting.
有趣。
All right, well, that's beyond this class.
好吧，那超出了这一类。
What we're going to see is how to cheat in blackjack.
我们将要看到的是如何在二十一点中作弊。
So this is going to be-- I encourage you to try this out
所以这将是-我鼓励您尝试一下
at casinos.
在赌场。
Just kidding.
开玩笑。
This is a little bit difficult to actually do in a casino
在赌场实际上很难做到这一点
unless you have an inside man.
除非你有内心的人。
So if you have an inside man, go for it.
因此，如果您有内心的人，那就去做吧。
It's guaranteed to win you lots of money
保证会为您赢得很多钱
because it's going to play optimally.
因为它将发挥最佳效果。
In perfect information blackjack,
在完美的信息二十一点中，
I suppose that I already know the entire deck.
我想我已经知道整个甲板了。
Suppose somehow either I get to put the deck there,
假设我要么把甲板放在那里，
or I have some x-ray vision.
或者我有一些X射线视力。
I get to see the entire deck ahead of time.
我可以提前看到整个甲板。
And then somebody's going to play
然后有人要去玩
through a game over and over with me-- or not over and over,
通过一遍又一遍的游戏-或一遍又一遍，
but until the deck is depleted-- and I
但是直到甲板耗尽为止
want to know in each case, should I hit,
想知道在每种情况下我应该打
or should I stand?
还是我应该站起来？
And I claim with dynamic programming
我声称采用动态编程
you can figure that out-- using exactly the same strategy
您可以使用完全相同的策略弄清楚
as text, actually.
作为文本，实际上。
It's really for each word, should I
这真的是每个单词，我应该
start a new line or not?
开始新的行还是没有？
Same problem here.
这里同样的问题。
It's slightly more complicated to write down.
写下来要稍微复杂一些。
So let's say the deck is a sequence of cards.
因此，假设卡片组是一系列纸牌。
And I'm going to call it c0, c1 up to cn minus 1, n cards.
我将其命名为c0，c1，最多cn减1，n张牌。
And you are one player.
而且你是一名球员。
First is the dealer.
首先是经销商。
I don't know how to solve this for two
我不知道如何解决两个
players, interesting open problem.
玩家，有趣的开放问题。
But for one player I can do it.
但是对于一个玩家我可以做到。
Let's say $1 bet per hand, I think they're called.
假设每手下注$ 1，我认为是跟注。
I'm not sure.
我不确定。
Per play?
每场比赛？
Per box?
每盒？
Whatever.
随你。
You're not allowed to double.
您不可以加倍。
You're not allowed to split.
您不允许拆分。
All these fancy rules are harder to think about,
所有这些花哨的规则都很难考虑，
although you might be able to solve them as well.
尽管您也可以解决它们。
So the idea is I have some cards.
所以想法是我有一些卡。
Should I hit or should I stand?
我应该打还是站着？
I don't know.
我不知道。
I'll guess.
我猜
So our guessing-- let's jump ahead to the guessing part--
所以我们的猜测-让我们跳到猜测部分-
is whether we want to hit or stand given a card.
是我们要击中还是站在卡片旁。
Actually, it would be easier to think
其实，想起来会更容易
about an entire play, an entire hand.
关于整个游戏，整个手。
We're going to guess, how many times should I
我们要猜测，我应该多少次
hit in the first play?
打第一部戏？
So initially, four cards are dealt.
因此，最初发了四张牌。
I look at my hands.
我看着我的手。
Actually, I don't really look at my hand.
实际上，我并不真正看我的手。
I'm just going to guess ahead of time.
我只是提前猜测。
I think I'll hit five times this time.
我想这次我会打五次。
I think I'll hit zero times this time.
我想这次我会打零。
I mean, I'm just going to try them all.
我的意思是，我将尝试所有这些。
So I don't really have to be intelligent here, OK?
所以我真的不必在这里变得聪明，好吗？
It's kind of crazy but it works.
这有点疯狂，但确实有效。
Our sub-problems, can anyone tell me
我们的子问题，谁能告诉我
what our sub-problems would be, In one word or less?
一个字或更短的字眼，我们的子问题是什么？
Less would be impressive.
少会令人印象深刻。
Yeah?
是啊
AUDIENCE: Where you start the new hand.
听众：从哪里开始新手。
PROFESSOR: Where do you start the new hand?
教授：您从哪里开始新手？
Yeah.
是的
So it's going to be suffixes of the cards.
因此，它将是卡的后缀。
So at some point we do a play, and then we get to ith card.
因此，在某个时候我们进行游戏，然后进入ith卡。
And then the rest of the game will be from the ith card on.
然后其余的游戏将从ith卡上开始。
So it's going to be suffix ci colon,
所以它将是后缀ci Colon，
I guess would be the notation here.
我想这是这里的符号。
It's a bit awkward.
有点尴尬
These are the cards that remain.
这些是剩下的卡。
And so the sub-problem is, what is the best play?
因此，子问题是，最佳发挥是什么？
What's the best outcome given $1 bets?
给定$ 1下注的最佳结果是什么？
How much money can I make-- maximize my winning, say--
我可以赚多少钱-最大化我的赢利-
given these cards onward?
给这些卡以后？
Who knows what happened to their earlier cards, but just
谁知道他们以前的卡怎么了，但是
these are the cards.
这些是卡。
I'm left with.
我留下了。
Number of sub-problems is-- hmm?
子问题的数量是-嗯？
n.
。
How many choices of i are there? n choices.
我有多少选择？ n个选择。
This really important.
这真的很重要。
It's really useful that we're thinking about suffixes.
我们考虑后缀确实很有用。
It's not that some subset of the cards have been played.
不是说纸牌的某些子集已经被玩过。
That would be really hard, because there's exponentially
那真的很难，因为
many different subsets that could be left.
可以保留许多不同的子集。
It's always a prefix that gets played,
它总是被播放的前缀，
and therefore suffix is left.
因此后缀被保留。
And there's only n suffixes, remember that.
而且只有n个后缀，请记住。
We're going to use it over and over in dynamic programming.
我们将在动态编程中反复使用它。
So now we need to solve the sub-problem.
因此，现在我们需要解决子问题。
Starting from ci, what's the best way to play?
从ci开始，最好的玩法是什么？
Well, the first four cards are fixed,
好吧，前四张卡是固定的，
and then we guess how many hits are left.
然后我们猜测还剩下多少个匹配
So it's going to be something like n minus i
所以它将是n减去i
minus four different possibilities for-- I mean,
减去以下四种不同的可能性-我的意思是，
that would be the maximum number of hits
那将是最大的点击数
I could take all the remaining cards.
我可以把剩下的所有卡都拿走。
That would be the most.
那将是最大的。
And let's see, so the number of choices-- I'll just say it's,
让我们看看，选择的数量-我只是说，
at most, n.
最多
I don't have to be fancy here.
我在这里不必花哨。
OK, now we go to the recurrence.
好的，现在我们来重复一下。
So I'm going to call this blackjack of i.
所以我要称呼我这个二十一点。
It's going to be the solution.
这将是解决方案。
I want to solve this sub-problem from i onwards.
我想从i开始解决这个子问题。
What's the best play?
最好的玩法是什么？
And I guess it's going to be a max if I'm measuring winnings.
而且我想如果我要衡量奖金的话，那将是一个最大的数目。
And what's the winnings if I decide to hit this many times?
如果我决定多次击中冠军，将会获得什么收益？
It's a little bit hard to write down the exact formula.
写下确切的公式有点困难。
I'm going to write a rough version which
我要写一个粗略的版本
is the outcome of that first play.
是第一场比赛的结果。
It's going to be either I lose $1, we tie, or I win $1.
要么我输了1美元，我们平手，要么我赢了1美元。
So if we end up with the same value,
因此，如果最终得出相同的值，
you actually-- in most versions--
您实际上-在大多数版本中-
you get your money back, nothing changes.
您取回了您的钱，没有任何变化。
The bet is nullified.
下注无效。
So that's a zero outcome.
所以这是零结果。
But if we're only betting $1, these
但是如果我们只下注$ 1，这些
are the three possible outcomes.
是三个可能的结果。
You can compute this, right?
您可以计算出来，对不对？
If I told you how many times you hit,
如果我告诉你你打了多少次
then you just execute through those cards
然后您只需通过这些卡执行
and you compute the values of my hand,
然后你计算出我的手的价值
of your hand versus the dealer's hand.
与经销商的手。
You see, did anyone bust?
你看，有人破产吗？
If so, they lose.
如果是这样，他们输了。
Otherwise you compare the values and you
否则，您将比较这些值，然后
see which is bigger or smaller.
看看哪个更大或更小。
This is easy to do in linear time.
这在线性时间内很容易做到。
No biggie.
没关系
What's useful here is that the dealer strategy
这里有用的是经销商策略
is deterministic.
是确定性的。
So after you know how many cards you take, what the dealer does
因此，在知道要取多少张卡之后，发牌人会做什么
is force, because he just looks.
是力量，因为他只是长相。
Do I have 17 or greater?
我是否有17岁或以上？
If not, take another card and keep repeating that.
如果没有，请再拿一张卡并继续重复。
So it's a deterministic strategy.
因此，这是一种确定性策略。
In linear time, you can figure out what the outcome is.
在线性时间内，您可以确定结果是什么。
Then you also have to add the outcome of all the remaining
然后，您还必须添加所有剩余的结果
cards, which is just BG of j.
卡，仅是j的BG。
This is recursion, super easy.
这是递归，超级容易。
We do this for all choices of j.
我们对j的所有选择都这样做。
It's like a range of i plus 4 up to n, I think.
我认为这就像是i加4到n的范围。
Sure, that'll work.
当然可以。
I should probably put an if here,
我可能应该在这里放一个
which is if it's a valid play.
这是一个有效的游戏。
There are some constraints here.
这里有一些限制。
If I've already busted, I can't hit again.
如果我已经破产，我将无法再打。
So in fact what you have to do in this for loop
所以实际上，您在此for循环中必须要做的
is say, well, maybe I take another hit.
是说，好吧，也许我会再受打击。
Maybe I take another hit.
也许我再受打击。
At some point I go over 21, and then you
在某个时候我超过21岁，然后你
have to stop the for loop.
必须停止for循环。
So I'm writing that as an if.
所以我写的是一个假设。
You can also do it with a break, however you want.
您也可以休息一下，但是可以。
But that's-- you're considering all possible options,
但这就是-您正在考虑所有可能的选择，
all valid options of play.
所有有效的游戏选项。
For each of them, you see what the outcome
对于每个人，您都会看到结果
was after the dealer takes some more cards.
是在发牌者再拿几张卡之后。
This is actually a little bit funny.
这实际上有点有趣。
Sorry, this should really be the number of hits in range
抱歉，这确实应该是范围内的点击数
from, let's say, 0 to n.
从0到n。
Maybe you don't hit at all.
也许您根本不打。
And then j is a little bit tricky,
然后j有点棘手，
because this is actually i plus 4 plus the number of hits
因为这实际上是我加4加上点击数
plus the number of dealer hits.
加上经销商点击数。
OK, so you have to run this algorithm
好，所以你必须运行这个算法
to compute what happened, which computes
计算发生了什么，计算
how many times a dealer took a card.
经销商拿了多少次卡。
That's how many cards got consumed.
那就是消耗了多少张卡。
And so that's-- if you do i plus 4 plus that plus that,
所以这就是-如果您这样做，我加4加那，
that's how many cards are left, or where the cards resume.
那就是剩下多少张卡，或者卡恢复的位置。
And then you call BG on that.
然后您致电BG。
So we're, in general, from BG of i--
因此，我们通常来自i的BG
if you think of the DAG-- there's some position,
如果您想到DAG-有一些立场，
maybe i plus 4 happens.
也许我加4发生了。
Maybe it doesn't happen.
也许不会发生。
It depends on what the dealer does.
这取决于经销商的行为。
We're going to depend on i plus 6, i plus 5 maybe.
我们将取决于我加6，也许我加5。
It's going to be all of these possibilities.
这将是所有这些可能性。
These are all different plays.
这些都是不同的戏剧。
And then on each of these edges, we're
然后在每一个边缘上，我们
going to have plus 1, 0, or minus 1.
将具有加1、0或减1。
Those are the outcomes, whether I won or lost or tied.
这些都是结果，无论我是赢还是输，还是并列。
And then we're just computing a shortest path in this DAG.
然后，我们只是在计算此DAG中的最短路径。
It's actually really easy if you think about it that way.
如果以这种方式考虑，这实际上非常容易。
This is just how many cards are left.
这就是剩余的卡数。
From that position, you just see what are all the possibilities?
从这个位置，您仅看到所有可能性？
What are all the edges that I could go to?
我可以去找哪些优势？
What states could I to go to next?
我可以进入下一个状态？
How many cards are remaining?
剩余多少张卡？
How much did it cost me or win me?
它花了我多少钱或赢得了我？
And then take longest paths in that DAG.
然后在该DAG中采取最长的路径。
That will give you the exact same answer.
那会给你完全相同的答案。
That's what this dynamic programming is doing.
这就是这种动态编程的目的。
In the lecture notes, there's more details where I actually
在讲义中，我实际上在哪里有更多详细信息
tried to write out this function, this recurrence
试图写出这个功能，这种重复
as an algorithm.
作为一种算法。
You could do it, assuming I've got everything right.
假设我一切正确，您可以做到。
It's not that hard.
没那么难。
The order here is just the same as the order we did before.
这里的顺序与我们之前的顺序相同。
The running time is going to be cubic in the worst case,
在最坏的情况下，运行时间将是三次的
because we have-- it's a little non-obvious,
因为我们有-这有点不明显，
but we have n sub-problems.
但是我们有n个子问题。
For each of them, we have n choices.
对于每个人，我们都有n个选择。
And for each choice we have to run the dealer strategy.
对于每种选择，我们都必须执行经销商策略。
And so that conceivably could take linear time.
因此，可以想象会花费线性时间。
Here I'm assuming a general value of 21.
在这里，我假设一般值为21。
If 21 is actually constant, it only
如果21实际上是常数，则仅
be constant time to play out a single hand,
保持不断发挥单手的时间，
and then it's quadratic time.
然后是二次时间。
So it depends on your model of generalized blackjack.
因此，这取决于您的广义二十一点模型。
But that's it.
就是这样。
And get some flavor of the power of dynamic programming,
并获得动态编程的力量，
we're going to see it's even more powerful than this
我们将看到它比这更强大
in the next two lectures.
在接下来的两个讲座中。